#### Dear Dan -

Nicole Rhoads at the News Service passed along the job posting for Web Designer at the College of Engineering.

I believe I have the strong understanding of web technologies that the position requires. My degree is in performing arts technology, a large part of which focused on computer programming, design, and media. Additionally, I have over four years of experience working as a web designer at the University of Michigan, so I'm confident I would be successful in this job!

In particular, I find the focus on new media, mobile platforms, and multimedia to be really interesting facets of this position. As a programmer with a degree that included audio and film, I love working with this sort of media integration.

Thanks for considering my application!

Ben Collins

# **Ben Collins**

## **Web Designer**

2324 Nixon rd, Ann Arbor MI - bencollins2@gmail.com - (734) 223-5428

## Work experience

## University of Michigan News Service

June 2007 -Present

Rewrote back end security, integrated Joomla template, designed multimedia slideshow

## Michigan Today

June 2007 -

Designed custom content management Present system

#### **University Record**

June 2007 -

Site maintenence, designed custom search engine, created custom ad server

#### Institute for Social Research

April 2008 -April 2009

Designed custom content management system, site maintenence, video editing

#### 40 Oz Sound

May 2007 -Sept 2008

Audio engineering, mixing, mastering and editing

## **Education**

Bachelor's degree

## University of Michigan

Performing Arts Techology 2004-2010

## Selected work

redesign

## U-M NS Custom Joomla template

Still in production. Screenshot at: http://ns.umich.edu/UM\_Redesign.png

Michigan Custom CMS

http://michigantoday.umich.edu

slideshow

## U-M NS Dynamic flash slideshow

http://ns.umich.edu/slideshows/commencement 10

Portfolio

### Online Additional work

http://bencollins.co

## Professional skills

## Coding HTML/CSS

Expert level experience writing clean, standards compliant code with focus on accessibility

### **Adobe Creative Suite**

I utilize Photoshop, Illustrator, and Dreamweaver for front-end design

#### Flash

Experience creating sites using Adobe Flash, including dynamic database interaction with ActionScript 3

## JavaScript/JQuery

Good working knowledge

#### CMS and PHP frameworks

Experience working with content management systems and frameworks including: Wordpress, Joomla, Drupal, Codelgniter, and Tumblr